A Guide to the Richmond Annexation Files 1942-1976
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Richmond Annexation Files 1942-1976
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 183
18.2 linear feet
Richmond Annexation Files
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The materials were originally deposited in the Department by John V. Moeser and Rutledge M. Dennis who used the materials to write The Politics of Annexation: Oligarchic Power in a Southern City(1982). The materials were then given to the Department by W.H.C. Venable, the primary lawyer involved in the trials, in 1983.
Biographical/Historical Information
"The legal battles fought over the 1970 Richmond annexation are considered by many observers, including attorneys in the U.S. Justice Department, as the most complex, prolonged, and far-reaching if any legal action triggered by municipal boundary expansion. For the Richmond power structure, the Holt suits quickly became much more than minor irritants. They had the potential to radically change the city's political landscape. What in past years involved fairly simple and straightforward strategies designed to maintain the political status quo now required, given the sophisticated legal challenges that Curtis Holt mounted against the city, equally sophisticated legal responses. The long cycle of action-response-reaction that characterized the sequence of events in the he courts was emotionally draining on both the participants and the observers. The information generated by the tedious research undertaken by attorneys for each side of the suits and by consultants versed in urban and regional planning, economics, and public administration, plus the lengthy depositions and courtroom hearings was comparable to that of a small library. The legal battle was made more complicated by the intricate routes traveled by the litigants and the fact that the routes at different points crossed each other, ran parallel to each other, and diverged at right angles. Journalists covering the cases over the years were hard pressed to summarize the proceedings in an intelligible fashion, as each year one case became more complicated or else was set aside as another equally complex case, was begun.
"The litigation began in February 1971 was Curtis Holt initiated his first suit contesting the annexation on constitutional grounds, and concluded over five and a half years later in November 1976 following a second Holt suit and a suit brought by the city. Litigation over annexation led to a U.S. Supreme Court order suspending local elections in Richmond that lasted five years and enabled the 1970 council, which was to serve until 1972, to continue in power for almost seven years. The arguments surrounding the various suits were presented to six different judicial bodies, the U.S. District Court in Richmond, a three judge district court in Richmond, a three judge district court in Washington, D.C., a Special Master in Washington, the Fourth Circuit Court of Appeals, and the U.S. Supreme Court...Holt's first suit (Holt I) against the city was successfully argued before the U.S. District Court in Richmond. The city, however, was successful in overturning the decision in the Fourth Circuit Court of Appeals. Holt's response was an appeal to the U.S. Supreme Court, but the high court denied the writ.
"Prior to the termination of the first suit, Holt brought a second suit (Holt II) against the city. Holt II was stayed by the federal court, though not before the Supreme Court had enjoined further city council elections. What prevented Holt II from moving forward was a suit which the city filed.
"The city's suit was itself complex, notwithstanding the confusion which was generated by the combination of the city's suit, Holt I, and Holt II. The city's suit was brought before a special three judge District Court in Washington which referred it to a Special Master for hearings and recommendations. Upon receiving the recommendation of the Master, the Washington court ruled against the city. The city appealed to the Supreme Court where, by Unanimous vote, the justices held that there was racial motive for the annexation. The Court also ruled, however, that, given the single-member council districts (Richmond had developed such a plan) and justifiable reasons such as economic or administrative benefits reaped by the city from the annexed area, the city could retain the annexed area. But, the city had to prove that such justifiable reasons existed and, moreover, had to revert to ward representation.
"The Supreme Court returned the case to the Washington District Court to determine whether verifiable reasons did exist. The Washington Court, once again, referred the case to the Special Master. The Master found that the city could prove that it received economic and administrative benefits from the annexed area and recommended, therefore, that the city retain the area. The Washington Court agreed with the recommendation of the Master and affirmed the annexation.
"After conferring with members of the city's black community and deciding that appeals and other legal action were only delaying the reinstatement of councilmanic elections, Holt did not appeal the decision to the Supreme Court...With the City's suit resolved, the injunction against elections were lifted and local elections were called for March 1, 1977. Furthermore, Holt II, which was stayed pending the outcome of the city's suit, was withdrawn by the Richmond District Court upon the request of both the city and Curtis Holt." excerpted from The Politics of Annexation, pp. 11-14.
Scope and Content Information
The materials cover the period 1942 to 1976 with the majority of the collection focusing on the period 1969-1975. Primarily notes, briefs, motion, replies and questions, the documents reflect the scope of the annexation trials of the 1970s of the City of Richmond. A large portion of the materials are not dated and others, because of the interdependency of the multiple trials described above, are as easily placed in one series as another. Documentation that may be of interest aside from the trial proceedings include; Comparative Population studies, Master Plans, Financial Reports for the City of Richmond, School Board Budgets and Reports, and city budgets.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Materials arranged in chronological order.
Organization
The collection has been weeded and arranged as closely as possible to reflect the separate legal actions involved in the Annexation of Chesterfield County and subsequent legal actions. Since the processing has occurred over time many of the folder heading do not accurately reflect the contents of the folders. The guide headings and folder numbers correspond to the actual folder numbers and contents. Although mistakes in arrangement have probably been made (there are some marked Holt III and IV for which there is no description) considerable effort has been expended to make the materials understandable.
Contents List
- Holt vs City of Richmond 1962-1975
  - Adminstrative Exhibits, Informal Memorandum of Law, Appellants' Brief, Appellant's Reply Brief 1972 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Answer 1974 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Appeals from US District Court for Eastern Virginia 1972 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Appellant's Brief 1974 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Appellants Reply Brief n.d. (Box-folder 1.5)
  - Appellee's Brief 1975 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - Appellee's Reply Brief/Appellee's Brief n.d. (Box-folder 1.7)
  - Appendices to Appellant's Brief n.d. (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Appendix n.d. (Box-folder 1.9)
  - Annexation Case Materials (1 of 3) n.d. (Box-folder 1.10)
  - Annexation Case Materials (2 of 3) n.d. (Box-folder 1.11)
  - Annexation Case Materials (3 of 3) n.d. (Box-folder 1.12)
  - Annexation Cases in the Virginia Supreme Court 1971 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - City Council Elections (clippings) 1962-1967 (Box-folder 1.14)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2) 1974 (Box-folder 1.15)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2) 1974 (Box-folder 1.16)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1.17)
  - Dan's Worksheets, Notes n.d. (Box-folder 1.18)
  - Dan's Worksheets n.d. (Box-folder 1.19)
  - Deannexation 1971 (Box-folder 1.20)
  - Deannexation Problems 1971-1973 (Box-folder 1.21)
  - Depositions--Bagley, Phil J., Jr. 1971 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - Depositions--Bassett, Leland 1971 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Deplsitions--Bliley, Thomas J., Jr. 1971 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Depositions--Burnett, Melvin W. 1971 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Depositions--Crowe, Morrill M. 1971 1971 (Box-folder 2.5)
  - Depositions--Daniel, William V. 1971 (Box-folder 2.6)
  - Depositions--Fitzgerald, Robert T. 1971 (Box-folder 2.7)
  - Depositions--Forb, Nathan J. 1971 (Box-folder 2.8)
  - Depositions--Horner, Irvin G. 1971 (Box-folder 2.9)
  - Depositions--Jones, George 1971 (Box-folder 2.10)
  - Depositions--Kiepper, Alan F. 1971 (Box-folder 2.11)
  - Depositions--Livingston, Ronald 1971 (Box-folder 2.12)
  - Depositions--Talcott, George R. and Bradshaw, Junie L. 1971 (Box-folder 2.13)
  - Depositions--Valentine, Henry L. II 1971 (Box-folder 2.14)
  - Depositions--Wheat, James Clifton, Jr. 1971 (Box-folder 2.15)
  - Depositions--Wilson, Charles P. 1971 (Box-folder 2.16)
  - Drafts 1974 (Box-folder 2.17)
  - Drafts of Arguments 1969 (Box-folder 2.18)
  - Exhibits, Administrative n.d. (Box-folder 2.19)
  - Exhibits, Financial n.d. (Box-folder 2.20)
  - Exhibits on Behalf of Defendants 1969 (Box-folder 2.21)
  - Exhibits on Behalf of Plaintiff 1971 (Box-folder 2.22)
  - Exhibits--Hx--1a City of Richmond Tax Study Commission Report 1971 (Box-folder 2.23)
  - Exhibits--Hx-2a City of Richmond Tax Study Commission Summary n.d. (Box-folder 2.24)
  - Exhibits-Hx-3a Impact of Federal Grant-in-Aid in Richmond 1971 (Box-folder 2.25)
  - Exhibits--Hx-4a Fiscal Impact of Residential and Commercial Development 1973 (Box-folder 2.26)
  - Exhibits--Hx-5a Personnel Alnalysis City of Richmond 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2.27)
  - Exhibits--Hx-6a Personnel Analysis City of Richmond 1970-1971 (Box-folder 2.28)
  - Exhibits--Hx-7a City Government and the Quality of Life in Richmond n.d. (Box-folder 2.29)
  - Exhibits--Hx-8a Project Report of the City Strategy Team 1972-1973 (Box-folder 2.30)
  - Exhibits--Hx-9a Salaries of Municipal Officials 1975 (Box-folder 2.31)
  - Exhibits--Hx-10a Quarterly Review of Departmental Budgets and work Program Objectives 1975 (Box-folder 2.32)
  - Exhibits--Hx-11a Organizational Chart 1974 (Box-folder 2.33)
  - Exhibits--Hx-12a Council-Citizen Authorities, Boards, Commissions and Committees 1975 (Box-folder 2.34)
  - Exhibits--Hx-13a Strengthening Management Organization 1971 (Box-folder 2.35)
  - Exhibits--Hx-14a Public Service and Work Program Analysis n.d. (Box-folder 2.36)
  - Exhibits--Hx-1f GRTC Cost Allocation and Schedule 1975 (Box-folder 2.37)
  - Exhibits--Hx-2f General Fund Revenue 1975 (Box-folder 2.38)
  - Exhibits--Hx-3f Analysis of City Expenditures 1975 (Box-folder 2.39)
  - Exhibits--Hx-4f General Fund Expenditures 1975 (Box-folder 2.40)
  - Exhibits--Hx-6f City Utilities and Payments to General Fund 1975 (Box-folder 2.41)
  - Exhibits--Hx-7f Analysis of RMA Impact 1975 (Box-folder 2.42)
  - Exhibits--Hx-8f Allocation of Cost of Education 1975 (Box-folder 2.43)
  - Exhibits 2.44 (Box-folder 2.44)
  - Exhibits-Hx-10f City Financing with Annexation 1975 (Box-folder 2.45)
  - Exhibits--Hx-11f Financial Detriment of Annexation (Alternate) 1975 (Box-folder 2.46)
  - Exhibits-Hx-12f Expenditures and Revenues by Department (v. I & II) (Box-folder 2.47)
  - Exhibits-Hx-13f Annual School Report, Financial Section Richmond 1975 (Box-folder 2.48)
  - Exhibits-Hx-14f Allocation of Debt Service Costs to the Annexed Area FY 1975 (Box-folder 2.49)
  - Exhibits--Hx-16f Financial Report of the Director of Finance 1970 (Box-folder 3.1)
  - Exhibits--Hx-20f Finance Director's Report 1975 (Box-folder 3.2)
  - Exhibits--Hx-28f Allocation of Departmental Expenditures 1975 (Box-folder 3.3)
  - Exhibits--Hx-29f RMA Prospectus 1971 (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Exhibits--Hx-30f RMA Prospectus 1973 (Box-folder 3.5)
  - Exhibits--Hx-31f RMA Annual Report 1975 (Box-folder 3.6)
  - Exhibits--Hx-13p Report-Assignment and Distiribution of Manpower, Stations and Companies (Bureau of Fire) December 1971 (Box-folder 3.7)
  - Exhibits--Px. 1 Racial Population Maps (Removed OS) 1940,1950,1960, 1971 (Box-folder 3.8)
  - Exhibits--Px.2 Census Tabulations 1930-1970 (Box-folder 3.9)
  - Exhibits--Px.3a Councilmanic Elections 1960 (Box-folder 3.10)
  - Exhibits--Px.3b Councilmanic Elections 1962 (Box-folder 3.11)
  - Exhibits--Px.3c Councilmanic Elections 1964 (Box-folder 3.12)
  - Exhibits--Px.3d Councilmanic Elections 1966 (Box-folder 3.13)
  - Exhibits--Px.3e Councilmanic Elections (Mixed precincts) 1966 (Box-folder 3.14)
  - Exhibits--Px.3f Councilmanic Elections (Black precincts) 1966 (Box-folder 3.15)
  - Exhibits--Px.3g Councilmanic Elections 1968 (Box-folder 3.16)
  - Exhibits--Px.3h Councilmanic Elections (Mixed precincts) 1968 (Box-folder 3.17)
  - Exhibits--Px.3i Councilmanic Elections (Black precincts) 1968 (Box-folder 3.18)
  - Exhibits--Px.3j Councilmanic Elections (New city) 1970 (Box-folder 3.19)
  - Exhibits--Px.3k Councilmanic Elections (Old city) 1970 (Box-folder 3.20)
  - Exhibits--Px.3m Councilmanic Elections (Old city Black) 1970 (Box-folder 3.21)
  - Exhibits--Px.3n Councilmanic Elections (Old city White) 1970 (Box-folder 3.22)
  - Exhibits--Px.4 Merger Vote Richmond-Henrico 1961 (Box-folder 3.23)
  - Exhibits--Px.6 Court Opinion and Final Order (Box-folder 3.24)
  - Exhibits--Px.8 Statements in Bill of Complaint n.d. (Box-folder 3.25)
  - Exhibits--Px9 Richmond Forward SCC Report n.d. (Box-folder 3.26)
  - Exhibits--Px.11 Trends in Age and Race Composition 1971 (Box-folder 3.27)
  - Exhibits--Px.12 Trends in Age and Race Composition 1960 (Box-folder 3.28)
  - Exhibits--Px.13 Memorandum on proposed compromise 1969 (Box-folder 3.29)
  - Exhibits--Px.14 Willey Consolidation bill 1968 (Box-folder 3.30)
  - Exhibits--Px.16 Community Renewal Program 1966 (Box-folder 3.31)
  - Exhibits--Px.17 Births/Deaths Natural Increase 1960-1964 (Box-folder 3.32)
  - Exhibits--Px.18 Population: Analysis of Richmond Regional Trends (Box-folder 3.33)
  - Exhibits--Px.19 Annexation Proceedings Richmond-Henrico 1970 (Box-folder 3.34)
  - Exhibits--Px.20 Population Density 1968 (Box-folder 3.35)
  - Exhibits--Px.21 Chesterfield Annexation Ordinance 61-334-288 1961 (Box-folder 3.36)
  - Exhibits--Px.22 Preliminary legal description of Annexation Compromise line (Horner-Bagley Line) n.d. (Box-folder 3.37)
  - Exhibits-Px.23a Plan of Government for the Richmond Region n.d. (Box-folder 3.38)
  - Exhibits--Px.23b Plan of Government for the Richmond Region Update 1969 (Box-folder 3.39)
  - Exhibits-Px.24 Mattox Report to Aldhizer Commission with Exhibits 1974 (Box-folder 3.40)
  - Exhibits-Px.26 Kiepper's Notes of Horner-Bagley Agreement 1969 (Box-folder 3.41)
  - Exhibits-Px.27a Report from Talcott to City Manager 1968 (Box-folder 3.42)
  - Exhibits--Px.27b Report from Talcott to City Manager 1968 (Box-folder 3.43)
  - Exhibits--Px.28 General Pertinent Date Horner-Bagley Line n.d. (Box-folder 3.44)
  - Exhibits--Px.29 Crusade for Voters 1968 (Box-folder 3.45)
  - Exhibits--29a Impact of Annexation on City Finances (Box-folder 3.46)
  - Exhibits--Px.32 Burnett notes of meeting with Kiepper 1968 (Box-folder 3.47)
  - Exhibits--Px.33 Griffin, Roger, C., Jr. n.d. (Box-folder 3.48)
  - Exhibits-Px.34 Resegregation in the Northside schools (Sartain Report) 1969 (Box-folder 3.49)
  - Exhibits--Px.36 Executive Secretary Chesterfield (Box-folder 3.50)
  - Exhibits--Px.41 Monthly Report of Personnel 1970 (Box-folder 3.51)
  - Fact-Finding Conclusions of Law and Plaintiff's Exhibits List 1971 (Box-folder 3.52)
  - Fiscal Information (Dan Robinson File) (1 of 3) (Box-folder 3.53)
  - Fiscal Information (Dan Robinson file) (2 of 3) (Box-folder 3.54)
  - Fiscal Information (Dan Robinson file) (3 of 3) (Box-folder 3.55)
  - Index and Summary of Transcript n.d. (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Interrogatory 5 A & B (Schools, Accounting) n.d. (Box-folder 4.2)
  - Memorandum of Appellants in response to questions 1972 (Box-folder 4.3)
  - Miscellaneous Holt III (1 of 5) 1971-1975 (Box-folder 4.4)
  - Miscellaneous Holt III (2 of 5) 1971-1975 (Box-folder 4.5)
  - Miscellaneous Holt III (3 of 5) 1971-1975 (Box-folder 4.6)
  - Miscellaneous Holt III (4 of 5) 1971-1975 (Box-folder 4.7)
  - Miscellaneous Holt III (5 of 5) 1971-1975 (Box-folder 4.8)
  - Motions n.d. (Box-folder 4.9)
  - Motions and Order n.d. (Box-folder 4.10)
  - Motions, Orders, etc. 1972 (Box-folder 4.11)
  - Newspaper Reports 1970-1971 (Box-folder 4.12)
  - Notes Holt II n.d. (Box-folder 4.13)
  - Miscellaneous Notes 1972-1975 (Box-folder 4.14)
  - Notes (Conference), Depositions and Interrogatories 1975 (Box-folder 4.15)
  - Notes and Exhibits 1971 (Box-folder 4.16)
  - Notes on Case n.d. (Box-folder 4.17)
  - Notes on City Administration n.d. (Box-folder 4.18)
  - Notes on Telephone Conversations 1971 (Box-folder 4.19)
  - Notes on Voting Rights Case Survey n.d. (Box-folder 4.20)
  - Order 1971 (Box-folder 4.21)
  - Points n.d. (Box-folder 4.22)
  - Proceedings 3-66 1972 (Box-folder 4.23)
  - Proceedings 3-75 1972 (Box-folder 4.24)
  - Proceedings 2-104 1974 (Box-folder 4.25)
  - Sub-Division Summary 1971 (Box-folder 4.26)
  - Tax Concerns 1971 (Box-folder 4.27)
  - Team of Progress 1972 (Box-folder 4.28)
  - Witnesses Testimony n.d. (Box-folder 4.29)
- City of Richmond V. County of Chesterfield n.d.,1968-1975
  - Chesterfield Annexation Study (Talcott) 1964 (Box-folder 5.1)
  - Chesterfield Annexation Study (Talcott) 1967-1968 (Box-folder 5.2)
  - Boundary Expansion Plans (Talcott) 1966 (Box-folder 5.3)
  - Exhibits Annexation Proceedings vol. I n.d. (Box-folder 5.4)
  - Exhibits Annexation Proceedings vol. II n.d. (Box-folder 5.5)
  - Notes 1973 (Box-folder 5.6)
  - Proceedings v.2 (3-179) 1968 (Box-folder 5.7)
  - Proceedings v.2 (40-239) 1969 (Box-folder 5.8)
  - Proceedings v.3 (180-394) 1968 (Box-folder 5.9)
  - Proceedings v.3 (240-451) 1969 (Box-folder 5.10)
  - Proceedings v.8 (1278-1481) 1969 (Box-folder 5.11)
  - Proceedings v. 10 (1560-1676) 1968 (Box-folder 5.12)
  - Proceedings (3354-3389) n.d. (Box-folder 5.13)
  - Proceedings v.26 (4781-4803) 1969, Oversize removal (Box-folder 5.14)
  - Trial Notes 1969 (Box-folder 5.15)
  - Trial Testimony n.d. (Box-folder 5.16)
- People involved n.d., 1968-1975
  - Aldhizer, n.d. (Box-folder 5.17)
  - Allen, Everette G., Jr. 1971 (Box-folder 5.18)
  - Anderson, Wayne Testimony n.d. (Box-folder 5.19)
  - Bagley, Philip Testimony n.d. (Box-folder 5.20)
  - Bassett, Leland n.d. (Box-folder 5.21)
  - Bliley, Thomas J., Jr. 1968 (Box-folder 5.22)
  - Bradshaw, Junie L. n.d. (Box-folder 5.23)
  - Burnett, Melvin 1968-1971 (Box-folder 5.24)
  - Byrne, L. Paul 1969 (Box-folder 5.25)
  - Carpenter, James n.d. (Box-folder 5.26)
  - Cheadle, n.d. (Box-folder 5.27)
  - Chittum, Edwin W. n.d. (Box-folder 6.1)
  - Crowe, Morrill M. n.d. (Box-folder 6.2)
  - Daniel, Bill n.d. (Box-folder 6.3)
  - Dodd, David R. Removed Map (Box-folder 6.4)
  - Dunn, B. Earl n.d. Questions (Box-folder 6.5)
  - Elmore, Spencer Transportation 1975 (Box-folder 6.6)
  - Forb, Nathan J. Notes n.d. (Box-folder 6.7)
  - Griffin, Roger 1970-1971 (Box-folder 6.8)
  - Horner, Irvin n.d. (Box-folder 6.9)
  - Jones, George Questions n.d. (Box-folder 6.10)
  - Kiepper, Alan Deposition and Testimony 1971 (Box-folder 6.11)
  - Lawler, Notes n.d. (Box-folder 6.12)
  - Leidinger, William Testimony (Box-folder 6.13)
  - Marsh, Henry L., III n.d. Notes and Background (Box-folder 6.14)
  - Miller, Eldon S. Dissertation and Documentation Oversized removed Brush and Refuse 1968-1975 (Box-folder 6.15)
  - Muller, Thomas n.d. 1974 (Box-folder 6.16)
  - Neena, Bill n.d. (Box-folder 6.17)
  - Oden, Philip W. 1971 (Box-folder 6.18)
  - Oslund, Margaret n.d. (Box-folder 6.19)
  - Pendleton, Don n.d. (Box-folder 6.20)
  - Ritz, Michael C. n.d. (Box-folder 6.21)
  - Robinson, Daniel A. n.d. (Box-folder 6.22)
  - Robinson, Fred Testimony and Transcript n.d. (Box-folder 6.23)
  - Scott, S. Buford n.d. (Box-folder 6.24)
  - Snyder, James C. 1975 (Box-folder 6.25)
  - Sutton, T. Dix TOP ,RF 1966-1968 (Box-folder 6.27)
  - Talcott, George Questions and Background 1962-1969 (Box-folder 6.28)
  - Talcott, George Testimony and Transcript 1976 (Box-folder 6.29)
  - Thornton, John 1968 (Box-folder 6.30)
  - Thornton, William S. n.d. Questions and Background (Box-folder 6.31)
  - Todd, A. Howe Testimony and Transcript 1976 (Box-folder 6.32)
  - Tuttle, Roger L. 1970-1971 (Box-folder 6.33)
  - Valentine, Henry III n.d., Questions and Background 1969 (Box-folder 6.34)
  - Vitae n.d. (Box-folder 6.35)
  - Watkinson, James S. Testimony n.d. (Box-folder 6.36)
  - Wells, n.d. Questions (Box-folder 6.37)
  - Wheat, Jim 1971 (Box-folder 6.38)
  - Woodward, Claude n.d. (Box-folder 6.39)
- City of Richmond v. United States of America n.d., 1969-1975
  - Administrative Analysis (Oslund, Margaret) 1974-1977 (Box-folder 6.40)
  - Administrative Benefits (Miller, Eldon) n.d. (Box-folder 6.41)
  - Answers, Interrogatories and Background Information 1975 (Box-folder 6.42)
  - Appeal 1974 (Box-folder 6.43)
  - Background n.d. (Box-folder 6.44)
  - Brief for Appellee's 1975 (Box-folder 7.1)
  - Department of Planning and Community Development 1968 (Box-folder 7.2)
  - Departmental Budget Quarterly Review 1975 (Box-folder 7.3)
  - Depositions--Bliley, Thomas J., Jr. and Thornton, William S. 1973 (Box-folder 7.4)
  - Depositions--Leidinger, William J. 1973 (Box-folder 7.5)
  - Depositions--Leidinger, Wharton (Leonard R.), Fary (Robert T.), Mattox (Conrad B., Jr.) and Talcott 1973 (Box-folder 7.6)
  - Depositions--Oslin, Dallas H., Jr. 1973 (Box-folder 7.7)
  - Depositions--Todd, A. Howe 1973 (Box-folder 7.8)
  - Depositions--Valentine, Henry Lee, II, Bliley and Todd 1973 (Box-folder 7.9)
  - Documents Request, Response to 1975 (Box-folder 7.10)
  - Elections--Primary and General (clippings) 1965 (Box-folder 7.11)
  - Exhibits 1974 (Box-folder 7.12)
  - Exhibits--Financial n.d. (Box-folder 7.13)
  - Exhibits--F-12 City of Richmond Capitol Budget 1975-1976 (Box-folder 7.14)
  - Exhibits--F-12 Survey (Box-folder 7.15)
  - Exhibits--F-13 Annual School Report Financial Section 1975 (Box-folder 7.16)
  - Exhibits--F-14 Daily Transaction Register 1975 (Box-folder 7.17)
  - Exhibits--F-15 Status of Object Accounts 1970 (Box-folder 7.18)
  - Exhibits--F-16 Status of Appropriation Accounts n.d. (Box-folder 7.19)
  - Exhibits--F-17 Daily trasaction register n.d. (Box-folder 7.20)
  - Exhibits--F-18 Monthly Status of Revenue Accounts 1975 (Box-folder 7.21)
  - Exhibits--F-19 Classification and Assessed Value of Taxable Property 1971 (Box-folder 7.22)
  - Exhibits--Financial Report of the Director of Finance 1974 (Box-folder 7.23)
  - Exhibits-F-21 Capitol Budget 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8.1)
  - Exhibits--F-21a Capitol Budget 1975 (Box-folder 8.2)
  - Exhibits--F-23 Capitol Budget Composite 1969-1975 (Box-folder 8.3)
  - Exhibits--F-24 Richmond Reports 1974-1975 (Box-folder 8.4)
  - Exhibits--F-25 Appropriations of Revenue 1974-1975 (Box-folder 8.5)
  - Exhibits--F-26 Tabulation of Individuals n.d. (Box-folder 8.6)
  - Exhibits--F-27 Revised Debt Service Cost of Allocations 1975 (Box-folder 8.7)
  - Exhibits--F-28 Financial Exhibits n.d. (Box-folder 8.8)
  - Exhibits--F-30 Instructions for Use of Voting Rights Survey Case Form n.d. (Box-folder 8.9)
  - Exhibits--F-33 Voting Rights Case 1976 (Box-folder 8.10)
  - Expansion Studies 1965 (Box-folder 8.11)